Register of the Kyril Drenikoff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Kyril Drenikoff papers
1849-2002
88009
Hoover Institution Archives
223 manuscript boxes, 42 oversize boxes, 1 cubic foot box, 14 card file boxes, 7 slide boxes, 2 oversize folders, 2 motion picture film reels, 22 sound cassettes, 1 videocassette, 106 sound discs, 1 microfilm reel, memorabilia (125.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, conference proceedings, reports, bulletins, serial issues, clippings, other printed matter, photographs, maps, other pictorial materials, and memorabilia, relating to the history and culture of Bulgaria, activities of the post-World War II Bulgarian émigré community, and activities of the World Anti-Communist League, the Anti-Bolshevik Bloc of Nations and other anti-communist organizations. Includes diaries of Georgi Drenikov, father of K. Drenikoff, and commander of the Bulgarian Air Force during World War II.
Drenikoff, Kyril
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material in this collection are available for immediate access. To access other sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1988.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (209 reels).
Biographical Note
1930 July 30 Born in Sofia, Bulgaria
1943 November 12 Gliding license
1948 High school diploma, Institut des Frères des Écoles Chrétiennes, Collège St. St. Cyrille et Méthode, Sofia, Bulgaria
1956 Law degree, State University, Sofia, Bulgaria
1957 June 5 Diploma in international public law, La Sorbonne, Paris, France
1959 March 2 Doctorat en droit international, La Sorbonne, Paris, France
1960-1965 In charge of programs in Bulgarian, Radio Vaticana
1960-1966 President, Association des Anciens Elèves des Frères des Ecoles Chrétiennes de la Bulgarie
1960 March 15 Diploma, Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales, Paris, France
1962 Bulgarian delegate to the Central Committee of the Anti-Bolshevik Block of Nations (ABN)
1962 June 24 Married Michèle Françoise Bihan-Faou
1962-1983 Member, Political Council of Simeon II, King of Bulgaria, and counselor to the King
1963 Degree, Hague Academy of International Law (International Law Fund laureate)
1965-1984 Chancellor of the Royal Bulgarian orders and decorations
1967-1968 State Counselor of Biafra
1968 Author, L'église catholique en Bulgarie Author (under the pseudonym of Strachimir Belphegoroff), La mort mystérieuse d'un roi
1970 Founder (with Ivan Drenikoff) and director, Centre de Recherches et de Documentation Balkaniques, Brussels, Belgium
1970-1983 Permanent Bulgarian representative to the World Anti-Communist League (WACL), and member of its council
1972 October 4 Allowed to use the name Kyril Drenikoff de Velboudj
1975 February 9 Became French citizen and allowed to use the name Cyrille Drenec
1978-1980 President, Ligue Bulgare des Droits de l'Homme
1981 Author, Bulgarska literatura v izgnanie
1982 Author, Bibliografi'i'a za Makedoni'i'a
1983 December 22 Died in Brussels, Belgium
Scope and Content Note
The Kyril Drenikoff papers constitute a major resource on Bulgaria and reflect Drenikoff's life and work as a writer, bibliographer, and political activist in the Bulgarian émigré community.
Kyril Drenikoff's involvement in that community is well documented in the extensive Correspondence series, as well as in several series dedicated to the activities of the World Anti-Communist League, the Anti-Bolshevik Block of Nations, and the Bulgarian League for Human Rights, organizations in which he held a prominent role. Material on other anti-communist organizations, such as the Assembly of Captive European Nations, can be found in the Subject File.
Another focus of the collection is Kyril Drenikoff's life-long interest in promoting Bulgarian history and culture. With his brother Ivan Drenikoff, he co-founded the Centre de Recherches et de Documentation Balkaniques, formerly named the Balkan Archives, for which they collected thousands of volumes. Kyril Drenikoff was also the publisher of Informations Bulgares and headed the Institut Culturel Bulgare, which published Edin Zavet. Much of his bibliographic effort was concentrated on Macedonia as well as on Bulgaria. Though of Macedonian origin, he strongly believed that the population of Macedonia is part of the Bulgarian nation and refuted the existence of an independent Macedonian nation and church.
Also important in the collection are Kyril Drenikoff's speeches and writings on Bulgarian and Macedonian culture, politics, and religious issues, often written under one of the following pseudonyms: D. B., D. D., K. G. D., D. G., D. K. G., D. L. G., G. G., D. V., Strachimir Belphegoroff, G. Bertram, Ieromonakh Danail, Konstantin Dragashov, Gavrets, Gavriil Gorianin, Dr. Gorski, K. D. Gueorguief, Serafim Ionov, Dimiter Iskrenov, S. Kirov, Kolezhanin, G. or Goge or Georgi Lazov, Iskren Ognianov, Pantelei Petnik, G. L. Starozemets, C. D. de Velboudj, and Iurdan Zambakov. Included in the Speeches and Writings series are Kyril Drenikoff's academic theses of 1959, 1960, and 1963, but his diaries, covering the period from 1971 to 1976, can be found in their own series.
Separate series were also created for King Simeon II of Bulgaria, to document Kyril Drenikoff's role as his counselor and member of his political council, as well as for King Simeon's father, Czar Boris III of Bulgaria. However, material relating to Czar Ferdinand I of Bulgaria can be found in the Subject File.
Apart from the Biographical File devoted to Kyril Drenikoff, there is a wealth of material related to several members of his family, in particular his brother, Ivan Drenikoff, and his father, Georgi Drenikoff, commander of the Bulgarian Air Force during World War II. Not only is Georgi's participation in both World Wars well documented, there is also material relating to his passion for gliding. Indeed, he founded the practice of gliding in Bulgaria and won the bronze medal in the gliding competition during the Olympic Games of 1936 in Berlin, the first Bulgarian Olympic trophy. An accomplished track athlete, he also set the 1924 Bulgarian national record in hurdle racing.
Finally, the collection is very rich in audio-visual material, with extensive series of photographs, postcards, maps, artwork, and sound recordings, relating mostly to Bulgarian history and culture.
Anti-Bolshevik Bloc of Nations.; Drenikov, Georgi.; World Anti-Communist League.; Anti-communist movements.; Bulgaria--Civilization.; Bulgaria--History.; Bulgaria.; Bulgarians in foreign countries.; Moving-pictures.; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.; Slides (Photography).; Video tapes.; World War, 1939-1945--Bulgaria.; World War, 1939-1945.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1930-1984 (Boxes 1-8)
  Scope and Contents note
  Address book, bibliographies, birth and marriage certificates, business cards, family correspondence, curricula vitae, decorations and diplomas, employment applications, identity cards, invitations, lists, notebooks, notes, obituaries, poems and songs, prayer, stamps, and subject file, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also: OVERSIZE FILE and SCRAPBOOKS.
  - Address book, 1978 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Bibliographies
    - Publications on Bulgaria, Balkans, the Catholic Church, the Orthodox Church, etc. (Folder 1: 2-6)
      General note
      See also: CARD FILE
    - Writings, translations, and interviews of Kyril Drenikoff, 1960-1983 (Folder 1: 7-11)
  - Birth and marriage certificates (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Business cards (Folder 2: 2-6)
  - Business cards (Box-folder 3: 1-5)
  - Business cards (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
  - Correspondence (family)
    - Undated (Folder 4: 3)
    - 1940-1942 (Folder 4: 4)
    - 1949-1950 (Folder 4: 5)
    - 1951-1959 (Folder 4: 6)
    - 1956-1966 (Folder 4: 7-8)
    - 1960-1964 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - 1967-1971 (Folder 5: 2)
    - 1972-1974 (Folder 5: 3)
    - 1982-1983 (Folder 5: 4)
  - Curricula vitae (Folder 5: 5)
  - Decorations and diplomas (Folder 5: 6)
  - Employment application to Radio Free Europe (Folder 5: 7)
  - Financial records relating to sales of books (Folder 5: 8)
  - Identity cards, driver's licenses, passports, visa applications
    - Undated (Folder 5: 9)
    - 1950s (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - 1960s (Folder 6: 2)
    - 1970s (Folder 6: 3)
    - 1980s (Folder 6: 4)
  - Invitations
    - General, 1959-1973 (Folder 6: 5)
    - King Simeon's wedding (1962) and 10th anniversary of his majority (1965), 1962, 1965 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Lists
    - Books read (Folder 6: 7)
    - Movies seen (Folder 6: 8)
  - Notebooks (Folder 6: 9)
    Consist mostly of proverbs, sayings, etc.
  - Notebooks (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Notes (Folder 7: 2-3)
  - Obituaries and condolence letters, 1983-1984 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Poems and songs (Folder 7: 5-6)
  - Prayer (Folder 7: 7)
  - Stamps (personal) (Folder 7: 8)
  - Subject file
    - Candidacy in the legislative elections of the 10th arrondissement in Paris, 1978 (Folder 7: 9)
    - Cycling, 1956-1964 (Folder 7: 10)
    - French nationality (Folder 7: 11)
    - Memberships
      - Military Order "Hospitalier de Saint-Lazare de Jérusalem,", 1965 (Folder 8: 1)
      - Ordre des Chevaliers du Rouvre, 1973 (Folder 8: 2-3)
        Includes correspondence with Giorgio G. Gherardi Dandolo
    - Refugee status in Italy (Folder 8: 4)
    - Studies
      See also: CORRESPONDENCE/Institut des Frères des Ecoles Chrétiennes and SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/"La Bulgarie dans les relations internationales entre les deux guerres mondiales," 1959; "La Dobroudja," 1960; and "Rapports entre OACI et les organisations aéronautiques européennes," 1963
      - Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales (Paris), 1956-1960 (Folder 8: 5-6)
      - Université de Paris (Folder 8: 7)
        Includes correspondence with Professor Charles Rousseau, 1958-1964
    - Use of name De Velboudj (Folder 8: 8)
      See also: Subject file/French nationality
  - Miscellany (Folder 8: 9-11)
- FAMILY FILE, 1911-2002 (Boxes 9-16)
  Biographical material related to members of the Drenikoff family. Includes correspondence, birth and marriage certificates, business cards, contracts, diaries, family book and family tree, identity cards and passports, memoirs, note books, notes, and writings, arranged alphabetically by name of family member and thereunder by physical form. See also: OVERSIZE FILE.
  - General (Folder 9: 1)
    Includes family book and family tree
  - Bedington (Drenikoff), Alexander (uncle) (Folder 9: 2-4)
    Correspondence, 1956-1982
  - Dombrovski, Dimiter (second cousin) (Folder 9: 5)
    Correspondence, 1957-1982
  - Drenikoff, Boris and Boyan (sons) (Folder 9: 6)
  - Drenikoff, Elena (grandmother), obituary, 1949 November (Folder 9: 7)
  - Drenikoff, Georgi (father)
    - Birth and marriage certificates (Folder 9: 8)
    - Business cards (Folder 9: 9)
    - Correspondence (mostly with family)
      - Undated (Folder 9: 10)
      - 1929 (Folder 9: 11)
      - 1931-1938 (Folder 9: 12)
      - 1939 (Folder 9: 13)
      - 1940-1949 (Folder 9: 14)
      - 1950-1952 (Box-folder 10: 1)
      - 1971-1975 (Folder 10: 2)
      - 1976-1979 (Folder 10: 3-4)
    - Diaries
      - Military service in the 8th German Air Force Corps, 1941 March 5 - June 5 (Folder 10: 5)
        Typescript
      - Pilot diary, 1943 August 10 - September 27 (Folder 10: 6)
        Holograph
    - Identity cards and passports (Folder 10: 7)
    - Legal documents
      - Court case, 1950 (Folder 10: 8)
        Includes verdict
      - Property, 1938-1951 (Folder 10: 9)
    - Memoirs
      Includes verses
      - Family, 1961-1969 (Folder 11: 1)
      - Personal
        - General, undated (Folder 11: 2)
        - "Avto Odiseia,", 1971 (Folder 11: 3)
    - Notebook (Folder 11: 4)
    - Notes (Folder 11: 5)
    - Pilot log books and licenses
      - 1928-1936 (Folder 11: 6)
      - 1935 (Folder 11: 7)
      - 1943 (Folder 11: 8)
    - Subject file
      - Chinese medicine, therapy, yoga (Folder 11: 9-10)
        See also: PHOTOGRAPHS
      - Gliding project for Branik (Bulgarian Youth Organization)
        - General, 1942 (Folder 12: 1)
        - Charts and drawings, undated (Folder 12: 2)
        - Clippings, 1929-1941 (Folder 12: 3)
        - Correspondence, 1931-1943 (Folder 12: 4)
        - Notes, undated (Folder 12: 5)
        - Orders and reports, 1935-1942 (Folder 12: 6)
        - Speeches, 1943 (Folder 12: 7)
        - Statute, undated (Folder 12: 8)
      - Military career
        - Certificates and awards, German Army, 1917-1941 (Folder 12: 9)
        - Lists
          - Deceased officers from Georgi Drenikoff's 38th graduation class from the Military Academy, 1927 (Folder 12: 10)
          - Pilots killed in action, 1938-1940 (Folder 12: 11)
        - Orders as Chief Commander of the Bulgarian Air Force, 1943-1944 (Folder 12: 12)
        - Program of the field and track competition, Kazanlok, 1942 (Folder 12: 13)
        - Report as Chief Commander of the Bulgarian Air Force, attached to the Headquarters of the VIII German Corps, 1941 March 4 - June 6 (Folder 12: 14)
    - Writings
      - General (Folder 12: 15-16)
      - "Pozitsionnata Voina I Gazovata Otbrana,", undated (Folder 12: 17)
      - "Edin zhivot za Bulgaria,", 1927 (Folder 12: 18)
  - Drenikoff, Ivan (brother)
    - Business cards (Folder 13: 1)
    - Certificate of school attendance, 1944 (Folder 13: 2)
    - Contracts with editors, 1975 (Folder 13: 3)
    - Correspondence
      - 1950 (Folder 13: 4)
      - 1960-1962 (Folder 13: 5)
      - 1963-1966 (Folder 13: 6)
      - 1964-1976 (Folder 13: 7)
      - 1967-1975 (Folder 13: 8)
      - 1968-1973 (Folder 13: 9)
      - 1968-1973 (Box-folder 14: 1)
      - 1970-1978 (Folder 14: 2)
      - 1977-1979 (Folder 14: 3)
      - 1977-1981 (Folder 14: 4)
      - 1980-1984 (Folder 14: 5-6)
    - Writings
      - Poetry, undated (Folder 15: 1)
      - Sayings, 1953 (Folder 15: 2)
      - "Khata yoga u nas,", 1963 (Folder 15: 3-4)
      - Konstantin Gospodariat na Velbuja, 2000 (Folder 15: 5)
        Printed copy
      - "Rilski orel,", 2002(?) (Folder 15: 6)
      - Georgi Drenikoff: Edin zhivot za Bulgaria, Sofia, 2002 (Folder 15: 7)
  - Drenikoff, Ivan Stoimenoff (uncle), 1951-1965 (Folder 15: 8)
    Includes his typewritten manuscript "Makhalata," 1951
  - Drenikoff, Michele (wife)
    - Certificates and diplomas, 1954-1978 (Folder 16: 1)
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Folder 16: 2)
      - 1965-1976 (Folder 16: 3)
    - Identity cards and driver's licenses, 1945-1969 (Folder 16: 4)
  - Drenikoff, Pepi Georgieva (mother)
    - Certificate of imprisonment, Sofia, 1949 November 23 (Folder 16: 5)
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Folder 16: 6)
      - 1927-1940 (Folder 16: 7)
      - 1946-1950 (Folder 16: 8)
      - 1980-1983 (Folder 16: 9)
    - Miscellany (Folder 16: 10)
  - Milenkova, Maria (great-grandmother), 1911-1937 (Folder 16: 11)
- DIARIES, 1971-1976 (Box 17)
  Diaries of Kyril Drenikoff, arranged chronologically.
  - 1971 (Folder 17: 1)
  - 1975 (Folder 17: 2)
  - 1976 (Folder 17: 3)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1947-1984 (Boxes 17-44)
  Personal correspondence of Kyril Drenikoff, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. See also: BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Correspondence (family).
  - Unidentified
    - Undated (Folder 17: 4)
    - 1950s (Folder 17: 5)
    - 1960s (Folder 17: 6)
    - 1970s (Folder 17: 7)
    - 1980s (Folder 17: 8)
  - Abramo, Léon, undated (Folder 17: 9)
  - Accademia Universale Umanesimo Nuovo (Roberto Guzzo), 1982 (Folder 17: 10)
  - Acone, Antonio ( Corriere africano), 1979 (Folder 17: 11)
  - Aféyan, Badrig, 1967-1972 (Folder 17: 12)
  - Ahpapov, D., 1982 (Folder 17: 13)
  - Aïvanhov, Omraam Michaël, 1972-1983 (Folder 17: 14)
  - Albertini, Georges, 1982-1983 (Folder 17: 15)
  - Alexieff, Gabriel, 1961-1972 (Folder 17: 16)
  - Altankov, Nikolay G., 1974-1982 (Folder 17: 17)
  - Amawi, Shakeeb (World Distributing Agency), 1983 (Folder 17: 18)
  - Amis du Centre Richelieu, 1957-1958 (Folder 17: 19)
  - Anastasoff, Christ ( Balkania), 1968-1977 (Folder 17: 20)
  - Anciens des Frères des Ecoles Chrétiennes de Bulgarie, 1964-1966 (Folder 17: 21)
  - Andrey, Reverend Metropolitan, 1971 (Folder 17: 22)
  - Angelov, Ivan, 1983 (Folder 17: 23)
  - Angelov, Nicola, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Angueloff, Demetrio, 1959-1983 (Folder 18: 2)
  - Anguèlov, Nicolay, 1974-1975 (Folder 18: 3)
  - Anne de Jésus, Révérende Mère, 1975-1964 (Folder 18: 4)
  - Annuaire français de droit international (Geneviève Guyomar), 1963-1970 (Folder 18: 5)
  - Antonow, Iwan, 1980 (Folder 18: 6)
  - Arsov, Boris Iliev, 1972-1974 (Folder 18: 7)
  - Aslanoff, Mr. (Institut des Etudes Slaves), 1969 (Folder 18: 8)
  - Assa, Aaron, 1968-1981 (Folder 18: 9)
  - Assiantchine, Alexander, 1957-1967 (Folder 18: 10)
  - Association des Auditeurs et Anciens Auditeurs de l'Académie de Droit International de La Haye, 1958-1973 (Folder 18: 11)
  - Association des Journalistes Périodiques Belges et Etrangers, undated (Folder 18: 12)
  - Association of Bulgarian Political Emigrés in Switzerland, 1977-1981 (Folder 18: 13-14)
  - Atanasov, Georgi, 1972-1979 (Folder 18: 15)
  - Athenoux, Andre, 1968 (Folder 18: 16)
  - Austin, Ludmila, 1964-1980 (Folder 18: 17)
  - Avramov, Assen, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
  - Azikiwe, N., 1968 (Folder 19: 3)
  - Bakaloff, D., 1956-1958 (Folder 19: 4)
  - Balabanoff, Nicolas, 1965 (Folder 19: 5)
  - Balabanski, Maximilian, 1962-1964 (Folder 19: 6)
  - Balev, Kalcho, 1969 (Folder 19: 7)
  - Bankov, Stephan, 1981-1982 (Folder 19: 8)
  - Bankovski, Ivan M., 1966-1983 (Folder 19: 9)
  - Barbaglia, Adriana and Virginio, 1961-1965 (Folder 19: 10)
  - Barev, Tsenko, 1977 (Folder 19: 11)
    See Bulgarski Zemledelski Naroden Soiuz
  - Bartell, Robert M. (Liberty Lobby), 1977 (Folder 19: 12)
  - Batcharoff, Pavel and Anna, 1957-1967 (Folder 19: 13)
  - Batut, C., undated (Folder 19: 14)
  - Baumont, Maurice, 1964 (Folder 19: 15)
  - Baytcheff, Captain, 1966 (Folder 19: 16)
  - Bellan, Bruno (Fronte Unitario Anticomunista), 1971-1980 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Bello, Enrico del, 1977-1978 (Folder 20: 2)
  - Beltrametti, Eggardo, 1974 (Folder 20: 3)
  - Benaroya-Sherwood, Mrs., 1968 (Folder 20: 4)
  - Benkov, Ivan, 1978-1979 (Folder 20: 5)
  - Bernard, Frère, 1974 (Folder 20: 6)
  - Berov, A.
    See Bulgarian-Makedonial Cultural Society "Izgnanik"
  - Berrier, Madeleine, 1960-1967 (Folder 20: 7)
  - Besher, Aysha, 1976-1980 (Folder 20: 8)
  - Biasibetti, Monique, 1982 (Folder 20: 9)
  - Biblioteca Civica, Verona, Italy, 1974 (Folder 20: 10)
  - Bibliothèque Nationale (Olivenbaum, Léo), Paris, 1967 (Folder 20: 11)
  - Blatchford, Irma Gabriella, 1958-1974 (Folder 20: 12-13)
  - Bliznakov, Emile, 1978-1979 (Folder 20: 14)
  - Bodsoy, Nicole, undated (Folder 20: 15)
  - Boissenin, Jean-Michel and Anastasia, 1957-1982 (Folder 20: 16)
  - Bojadjieff, Maria Anguelova, 1960 (Folder 20: 17)
  - Bojadjieff, Jordan, 1976 (Folder 20: 18)
  - Bojadzhiev, Emil, 1980 (Folder 20: 19)
  - Bonavita, Erminia (Chicchi), 1961-1964 (Folder 20: 20)
  - Bonnet, Rachel, 1958 (Folder 20: 21)
  - Bosch, Vincent van den, 1981 (Folder 20: 22)
    Includes his article "Le dictateur"
  - Boudier, Thuy, undated (Folder 20: 23)
  - Boumard, Marie-Cécile, 1959 (Folder 20: 24)
  - Boutemail, Pierre-Hervé, Mrs., 1956-1960 (Folder 20: 25)
  - Boyadjieff, Christo, 1968-1983 (Folder 20: 26)
  - Boysson, Gaëtan and Edith de, 1956-1960 (Folder 20: 27)
  - Braglia, Erika, 1972-1978 (Folder 20: 28)
  - Brizay, Jean-Pierre (Michaud Brizay Pestel-Debord), 1982 (Folder 20: 29)
  - Broucayrol, Jacqueline, 1958 (Folder 20: 30)
  - Bulgarian-Makedonial Cultural Society "Izgnanik,", 1970-1971 (Folder 20: 31)
  - Bulgarian National Front, 1949-1981 (Folder 20: 32)
  - Bulgarski Zemledelski Naroden Soiuz, 1973-1981 (Folder 20: 33)
  - Bureau d'Accueil & d'Information pour les Etudiants Etrangers, 1957 (Folder 20: 34)
  - Cailly, Miss, 1956 (Folder 20: 35)
  - Carle, Rémy, 1957 (Folder 20: 36)
  - Catholic Church, 1971 (Folder 20: 37)
    Includes correspondence with Cardinal Angelo dell'Acqua and several others, relating mostly to the Catholic Church in Bulgaria
  - Centre d'Education Politique (Conférence Olivaint), 1958-1960 (Folder 20: 38)
  - Chalukoff, Dimiter and Judith, 1970 (Folder 20: 39)
  - Chantraine, Alexis and Jeanne, 1956-1972 (Folder 20: 40)
  - Chappée, Louis, Mrs., 1961 (Folder 21: 1)
  - Charles-Vincent, Frère, 1957 (Folder 21: 2)
  - Charron, René, 1957-1966 (Folder 21: 3)
  - Chassaignon de Cazes, Valentine, 1974 (Folder 21: 4)
  - Chefakat, Francesca, 1983 (Folder 21: 5)
  - Cheng, Wei-yuan, 1983 (Folder 21: 6)
  - Chenkov, Georgi, 1964-1966 (Folder 21: 7)
  - Cheysson, Claude, 1975-1979 (Folder 21: 8)
  - Chobanov, Gancho, 1971-1975 (Folder 21: 9)
  - Chopova, Mira, undated (Folder 21: 10)
  - Christoff, Nancy, 1974
  - Christophorov, Pierre and Nadia, 1968-1972 (Folder 21: 11)
  - Christov, Boris, 1970 (Folder 21: 12)
  - Christov, Luben M., 1965-1968 (Folder 21: 13)
  - Christov, Milko, 1974-1983 (Folder 21: 14)
  - Chrobok, Bronislaw, Mrs. (Princess Maria Luisa of Bulgaria), 1964-1971 (Folder 21: 15)
  - Cino del Duca, S., Mrs., 1969 (Folder 21: 16)
  - Civiltà cristiana, 1976-1978 (Folder 21: 17)
  - Cliquet, René, Mrs. (Poucette), 1982-1983 (Folder 21: 18)
    See also: SUBJECT FILE/Amitiés Belgo-Chinoises
  - Coêlho, Anamaria and Osvaldo, 1958-1961 (Folder 21: 19)
  - Comité International pour la Défense des Droits de l'Homme en U.R.S.S., undated (Folder 21: 20)
  - Conseil Représentatif des Juifs de France (Moch, M.), 1969 (Folder 21: 21)
  - Cou, Georges, undated (Folder 21: 22)
  - Cristofv, Daphne Kremena, 1965-1978 (Folder 21: 23-24)
  - Cukier, Marysia, 1980 (Folder 21: 25)
  - Cuny, Hubert, 1972 (Folder 21: 26)
  - Dachy, Marc, 1983 (Folder 21: 27)
  - Dami, Aldo, 1975-1977 (Folder 21: 28)
  - Dandulova, Raina, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Darby, Douglas and Esmi Jean, undated (Folder 22: 2)
  - David, Paul, 1962-1963 (Folder 22: 3)
  - Davidoff, David, 1967-1981 (Folder 22: 4)
  - Davidov, Albert, 1965 (Folder 22: 5-6)
  - Déjardin, Léon, 1956-1962 (Folder 22: 7)
  - Delabarre, Colette and Pierre, 1984 (Folder 22: 8)
  - Delpey, Roger, 1966-1968 (Folder 22: 9)
  - Deltcheff, Pierre, 1974-1982 (Folder 22: 10)
  - Democrazia Cristiana (Fincati, Claudio), Rome, 1962 (Folder 22: 11)
  - Derebanova, Eli, 1970-1979 (Folder 22: 12)
  - Desris, John (Cross Publications), 1969 (Folder 22: 13)
  - Didoff, Gueorgui, 1968-1976 (Folder 22: 14)
  - Dilovski, Ivan, 1982 (Folder 22: 15)
  - Dimanow, Theodor, 1971-1972 (Folder 22: 16)
  - Dimitrieva, B., 1969 (Folder 22: 17)
  - Dimitroff, G. M., 1948-1970 (Folder 22: 18)
  - Dimitroff, Ivan and Tsvetanka, 1967-1969 (Folder 22: 19)
  - Dimitroff, Pachanko, 1966 (Folder 22: 20)
  - Dimitroff, Pavel, 1961-1968 (Folder 22: 21)
  - Dimitroff, Stancho, 1972 (Folder 22: 22)
  - Dimitroff, Ventseslav, 1975-1982 (Folder 22: 23)
  - Dimitrov, Boris, 1971-1980 (Folder 23: 1)
  - Dimitrov, D., 1983 (Folder 23: 2)
  - Dimitrov, Ivan, 1968-1959 (Folder 23: 3)
  - Dimitrov, Jordan and Johanka, 1965-1969 (Folder 23: 4)
  - Dimizkov, Stanislav Kostov, 1957-1964 (Folder 23: 5)
  - Dobruszkes, A., 1983 (Folder 23: 6)